<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-09T14:57:55-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">&amp;amp; life doesn’t stop for anybody.</title><subtitle>just me, hello
</subtitle><author><name>hava parker</name></author><entry><title type="html">on ‘stranger in the alps’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/on-stranger-in-the-alps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="on 'stranger in the alps'" /><published>2019-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/on-stranger-in-the-alps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/on-stranger-in-the-alps.html">&lt;p&gt;something about this spring drew me to Sad White Girls on guitar - maybe it was los angeles’ uncharacteristic raininess (the drought is over; thank christ?) or the realization that i was rapidly closing in on the end of my second year at college. or, more likely, it was that i was beginning to get bored of listening to bon iver’s 2011 self-titled. i can almost hear my fellow indie fans - &lt;em&gt;bored? of bon iver?&lt;/em&gt; - yeah. i know. shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;however it happened, i landed on the pitchfork-acclaimed group &lt;a href=&quot;https://xboygeniusx.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;boygenius&lt;/a&gt;, fell in love, and gradually trickled down into the group’s three musicians. but i’ll talk about julien baker’s wide-mouthed belt and lucy dacus’ lo-fi another day. today is about phoebe bridgers. (and &lt;em&gt;stranger in the alps&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;smoke signals serves as a slow open. lyrically, this shines as an introduction to phoebe bridgers; its several references to various musicians (bowie, the smiths, mötorhead) and thoreau give an immediate picture of her artistic sensibilities and influences. somehow, she manages to mention others’ works in every verse without coming off as boastful or hackneyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;despite bridgers’ lyric honesty, i notice more and more that she functions as a passive character in the majority of her music; the observant eye, hurt by and curious about the world around her. “smoke signals” emphasizes this through various means. at first it seems like it’s because she discusses so many people who &lt;em&gt;aren’t&lt;/em&gt; her (marshall, who the song is written about; bowie, the smiths, etc., etc.), and then it seems like it’s just because the song is so sedate. but then when bridgers hits the final verse, the only one solely about herself, the song gains a new energy just before it comes to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;perhaps my favorite moment of the song is its very end. the final word (“wall”) ricochets within the song’s chamber-like confines, before being absorbed and silenced by the four-hit bass riff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at this point, “motion sickness” is bridgers’ signature song; much like the mainstream was introduced to electropop princess &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grimesmusic.com/&quot;&gt;grimes&lt;/a&gt; by way of her relationship with elon musk, bridgers’ name was briefly known in relation to the media circus that developed around ryan adams. of course, she is more than The Girl, Who Talked About Ryan Adams.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hava parker</name></author><summary type="html">something about this spring drew me to Sad White Girls on guitar - maybe it was los angeles' uncharacteristic raininess (the drought is over; thank christ?) ...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a3164574832_10.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a3164574832_10.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">a blueprint: filmspotting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/a-blueprint-filmspotting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a blueprint: filmspotting" /><published>2019-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/a-blueprint-filmspotting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-blueprint-filmspotting.html">&lt;p&gt;hello blog. how’re you doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;today marks a month until i get back to school, and i’ve decided something monumental: it is, at last, time to get through the movies i’ve been stockpiling for YEARS. for all the random pieces of media i’ve consumed, as i get older, i realize just how many things i wasn’t fully awake/cognizant for. hopefully i’ll fix that in the remaining time i have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’ll possibly write up thoughts about things as i go; we will see. inb4 this just absolutely wrecks my critical opinions of things i love. chances are that i end up harping on brat pack movies all summer instead of getting through any of the list below, but you know. life, uh, finds a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;films-in-no-particular-order&quot;&gt;films, in no particular order:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;a clockwork orange &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1971, dir. stanley kubrick)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; last time i watched this was after i soberly endured an especially annoying collegiate rager. i fell asleep halfway through, exhausted from babysitting college students five years older than myself. i figure i should revisit.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;eternal sunshine of the spotless mind &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2004, dir. michael gondry)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; because every movie list on the internet lists this as a must-see modern classic. also, i'm very excited to see jim carrey in a non-slapstick role. to a lesser extent, i'm hyped for watching kate winslet play a contemporary character.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;good will hunting &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1997, dir. gus van sant)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; just wanted an excuse to rewatch.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;stand by me &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1986, dir. rob reiner)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; a movie that i used to watch all the time and felt weirdly tied to because wil wheaton hails from my mom's hometown.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;donnie darko &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2001, dir. richard kelly)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; my best friend when i was 13 told me i HAD to watch this, and when i kept forgetting to, she relented and made me listen to echo and the bunnymen's &quot;the killing moon&quot; (one of the movie's two signature songs) many more times than i ever wanted to.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;reality bites &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1994, dir. ben stiller)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; one of my mom's favorites. here because winona ryder, but also because its credits song (&quot;stay&quot; by lisa loeb) is another favorite of my mother's and was reportedly an obsession of mine as a child. basically, this has a lot of significance for me, especially for a movie that i've never actually seen.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;the grand budapest hotel &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2014, dir. wes anderson)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; wes anderson. watched this when i'd come down with this horrific fever, in between episodes of bbc sherlock.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;cinema paradiso &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1988, dir. giuseppe tornatore)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; provides some nice foreign film flavor (or, as i call it, *fff*). my mom won't shut up about this one.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;sixteen candles &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1984, dir. john hughes)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; the only brat pack movie that i don't know by heart. the buck stops here.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;little miss sunshine &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2006, dir. valerie faris/jonathan dayton)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; saw this years and years ago and remember it far more vividly than the many other movies i watched at the time (many of which have ended up on this list). baby abigail breslin and the weird campiness that i've come to love in Cinema&amp;trade;.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;500 days of summer &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2009, dir. marc webb)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; another one that i'd been wanting to rewatch.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;fight club &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(1999, dir. david fincher)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; because somehow i haven't already seen/read this?&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;dancer in the dark &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2000, dir. lars von trier)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; bjork.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;ruby sparks &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2012, dir. valerie faris/jonathan dayton)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; same directorial team as &lt;em&gt;little miss sunshine&lt;/em&gt;! anyway - tumblr of a few years ago was obsessed with this one's meta-ness and commentary on the manic pixie dream girl stereotype and all that. also, i have a soft spot for zoe kazan after a roommate i had a strenuous friendship with forced me to watch &lt;em&gt;the big sick&lt;/em&gt; for her birthday.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtitle&quot;&gt;roma &lt;span class=&quot;mdesc&quot;&gt;(2018, dir. alfonso cuarón)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; meant to watch it right when it was picking up popularity/acclaim, forgot as i always do, etc. etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>hava parker</name></author><summary type="html">today marks a month until i get back to school, and i've decided something monumental: it is, at last, time to get through the movies i've been stockpiling for YEARS.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i0.wp.com/thespool.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/reality.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i0.wp.com/thespool.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/reality.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>